ABDULLAH AL MARUF

Software Engineer

Passionate software engineer with 2 years of working experience developing Kubernetes tools in GO. Acted as AppsCode's KubeDB project head for more than a year. Love to participate in programming contests. An enthusiastic team player.

\geq	maruf.2hin@gmail.com
	+8801722777603
Ç	Dhaka, Bangladesh
	https://maruftuhin.com
C	github.com/the-redback
ir	linkedin.com/in/maruftuhin

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

AppsCode Ltd. 🗗

May, 2017 - Present

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Subsidiary company of AppsCode Inc. USA. An Integrated platform for collaborative coding, testing & deploying containerized apps.

- Worked on Kubernetes client-G0 to build third party containerized tools.
- Worked on KubeDB tool. Conducted Bi-Weekly KubeDB Community meetings regularly. Acted as KubeDB project head for more than a year. Got involved in other projects too.
- Worked on Pixel Tracking [web beacon], different APIs of mainstream cloud providers, etc.
- Created and used Kubernetes cluster on all the mainstream cloud providers, like, aws, gcs, azure, digitalocean etc.
- Experienced many Kubernetes tools.

Intern

AppsCode Ltd. (Former The TigerWorks Pvt. Ltd.)

1st January, 2016 – 15th January, 2016

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- 2 weeks long internship program.
- Implemented an email verification tool in Java.

PROJECTS

KubeDB 🗷

- A tool to automate database deploy on Kubernetes. It also takes scheduled backup for databases.
- Added MongoDB, MySQL, Redis and Memcached support to KubeDB.
- Also worked on PostgreSQL and MongoDB clustering system.

Appscode/Analytics 🗹

- Worked with docker-hub APIs to collect analytic data and stored them in Google sheets using GO client.
- Used pixel tracking [aka, web beacon] to event each view of GitHub or other web pages in real time.

3D Racing Game 🗷

- Final year thesis & project.
- Developed for both PC and Android.
- Tools: Unity 5 Game Engine, Android SDK, C#.

Academic Projects

- Department of Student Welfare (DSW) Management System using C# and MySQL.
- Library Management System using C# and Microsoft SQL Server.
- Scientific Calculator using Java swing.
- Automatic Email Verification using Java as Internship Project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS



EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Science & EngineeringChittagong University of Engineering & Technology

Session: 2011-12

Chittagong, Bangladesh

ACHIEVEMENTS

Competitive Programming (June, 2012 – Present)

- Solved overall 900+ problems on different Online Judges.
- Participated and became divisional champion in 2 ICPC Dhaka Regional (ICPC-2014 & ICPC-2015).
- Got 6th position at national level IUPC-2016 at SUB
- Got 1st position at regional IUPC-2015 at USTC and also performed well in other national and divisional contests.

Open Source Contribution (May, 2017 - Present)

Contributed on open source projects including Kubernetes, KubeDB, appscode/osm, appscode/kutil, appscode/analytics etc.

Extra Curriculum

- Former President of CUET Computer Club.
- Former member of CUET Debating Society.
- Organizer of CUET CSE FEST 2015 and CUET NCPC 2016.
- Attended many self-developing training courses.

STRENGTHS

Team Work	
Optimist	
Communication	
Problem Solving	
Self Learning	
Tech Savvy	

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Competitive Programming History Photography

Gaming Traveling